waterpik.com 2016-10-21

# Website Privacy Policy | Water Pik, Inc.

## Last modified March 16, 2015

**THIS WATER PIK, INC. WEBSITE PRIVACY POLICY ("PRIVACY POLICY") PERTAINS TO YOUR ACCESS AND USE OF THE WATERPIK.COM WEBSITE (THE "SERVICE"). IT DOES NOT APPLY TO YOUR USE OF THE ONLINE STORE WHICH IS OPERATED BY A THIRD PARTY AND SUBJECT TO A SEPARATE PRIVACY POLICY. PLEASE READ THIS PRIVACY POLICY ("PRIVACY POLICY") CAREFULLY BEFORE ACCESSING OR USING THE SERVICE.**

The Service is operated by Water Pik, Inc. ("we," "our" and "us"). This Privacy Policy describes the information collected from users who access the WATERPIK.COM website ("you"), how we use it, how we share it, how we protect it, and the choices you can make about your information.

ATTENTION: ACCESSING OR USING THE SERVICE INDICATES THAT YOU ACCEPT AND AGREE TO BE BOUND BY THIS PRIVACY POLICY IN FULL. IF YOU DO NOT ACCEPT THIS PRIVACY POLICY, DO NOT ACCESS OR USE THE SERVICE. You acknowledge (a) that you have read and understood this Privacy Policy; and (b) this Privacy Policy shall have the same force and effect as a signed agreement.

Please review the Privacy Policy each time you use the Service. BY USING THE SERVICE, YOU AGREE TO BE BOUND BY THE MOST RECENT VERSION OF THE PRIVACY POLICY. If we materially change this Privacy Policy, we’ll let you know by updating the policy and its modification date on the websites that are part of the Service.

## I. Information We Collect

We collect information from you when you use the Service, contact or interact with us or fill out a registration form or survey. When calling us, your telephone number, name, and other information needed to respond to your request may be collected.

When you access and use the Service, we may collect your name, address, email address, telephone number, country, gender, model number and serial number of purchased products, product purchase information, and any other information that you provide in using the Service. 

You may use some portions of the Service anonymously, though we automatically collect information regarding each user of our Service, which may include your Internet Protocol (IP) address, the domain name of your Internet service provider, mobile device information, the Service features and webpages you use and access and the time of your use, the type of Internet browser and operating system you are using, the referring site, application or service, and aggregated information that cannot be used to specifically identify you when you use the Service. For more information about automatic collection of personal information, see the Analytics and Cookies sections below.

We may receive information about you from third parties and combine all of the information we collect from or about you and use it in the manner described in this Privacy Policy.

## II. How We Use Your Information

**We use the information that we collect for several purposes, including:**

  * The purposes for which you provided it;
  * To provide products and services to you;
  * To ship prizes to contest winners;
  * To process and respond to your inquiries and comments (such as responding to customer service or warranty emails or product registration submissions);
  * To send you information about your relationship or transactions with us;
  * To personalize and enhance your experience using the Service;
  * To send periodic newsletters, surveys, promotions and other emails that directly promote the use of the Service if you opt-in to receive our emails;
  * To develop new products and services;
  * To generate and review reports and data about our user base and service usage patterns;
  * To compile aggregate data for internal and external business and research purposes;
  * To reduce credit risk;
  * To prevent fraud and abuse of the Service and to otherwise protect users and visitors and our business;
  * To assist law enforcement and respond to subpoenas;
  * To administer, operate, and improve the Service and for internal business purposes; and
  * To perform other business activities as needed, or as described elsewhere in this Privacy Policy.
  * As explained elsewhere in this Privacy Policy, personal information we collect may be processed by our partners in providing related services to the Service (including, but not limited to, email and website analytics services and administration and technical services relating to the warranty, replacement, and servicing of our products).

## III. How Your Information is Disclosed

Information may be disclosed to third parties in accordance with our Privacy Policy. Please note that a user may choose not to share certain information as described in "Your Choices Regarding Your Information" below. 

### A. Third Party Service Providers and Business Partners

We may use third party service providers and business partners to perform functions in connection with the Service, such as functions related to analyzing and improving the Service usefulness, reliability, user experience and operation, email services, product warranty services, remarketing, product reviews, and contest administration. We also may share information about you that these third parties need to perform their functions and in accordance with our agreements with them. For example, a third party service provider operates the Online Store and manages warranty services for our products. We may share your information with such service provider for product returns, replacements and other warranty services.

### B. Business Changes

If we become involved in a merger, acquisition, sale of assets, joint venture, securities offering, bankruptcy, reorganization, liquidation, dissolution, or other transaction or if the ownership of all or substantially all of our business otherwise changes, we may transfer your information to a third party or parties in connection therewith. 

### C. Affiliates

We may also share your information with our affiliates for purposes consistent with this Privacy Policy. Our affiliates will be required to maintain that information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

### D. Investigations and Law

We may disclose information about you to third parties if we believe that such disclosure is necessary to:

  * Investigate fraud and abuse of the Service;
  * Take action regarding suspected illegal activities;
  * Enforce or apply this Privacy Policy or other agreements with us;
  * Comply with the law or guidance and cooperate with government or law enforcement officials or private parties;
  * Protect our rights, reputation, safety, and property, or that of users or others;
  * Respond to claims and legal process (for example, subpoenas); and/or
  * Protect against legal liability.

### E. Aggregated Information

We may share aggregated information relating to users of the Service with affiliated or unaffiliated third parties for internal and external business and research purposes. This aggregated information does not contain personal information about any user.

### F. Analytics

We use third-party analytics tools to help us measure traffic and usage trends for the Service. These tools may use cookies and other technologies to collect information about your use of the Service and your preferences. These tools collect information sent by your device or the Service and other information that assists us in improving the Service. This information may be used to, among other things, analyze and track data, serve content, determine the popularity of certain content, and better understand your online activity.

We use Google Analytics, Crazy Egg, and other analytics providers to better understand who is using the Service and how people are using it. These tools use cookies to collect and store information such as website pages visited, places where users click, time spent on each website page, IP address, type of operating system used, location-based data, device ID, search history, and phone number. We use this information to improve the Service and as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. Please see <http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/> for details about how Google uses this information, and visit <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout> for information about the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on. Please see <http://www.crazyegg.com/privacy> for details about how Crazy Egg uses this information, and visit <http://www.crazyegg.com/opt-out> for information about opting out of Crazy Egg’s services. 

## IV. Cookies

Cookies are small files that a website or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your web browser (if you allow it) that enable the website’s or service provider’s system to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. You can instruct your browser to stop accepting cookies. However, if you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use all portions of all functionality of the Service.

  * Persistent cookies remain on the visitor’s computer after the browser is closed.
  * Session cookies exist only during a visitor’s online session and disappear when the visitor closes the browser software.

We use cookies on the Service to help us compile data about website traffic and website interaction so that we can offer better website experiences and tools in the future.

Some of our business partners, such as our web analytics providers, reviews providers, and our remarketing providers, may also use cookies, pixel tags, beacons, tags or scripts on our websites, some of which may track users across websites and over time. Product reviews are managed by Bazaarvoice, Inc. Their privacy policy is available at [ http://www.bazaarvoice.com/privacy-policy/](http://www.bazaarvoice.com/privacy-policy/). 

## V. Security

We implement a variety of security measures to protect the safety of your personal information when you use the website, enter, submit, or access your personal information, including encryption and firewalls. 

While we take reasonable measures to protect the information you submit via the Service against loss, theft, unauthorized use, disclosure, or modification, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. No Internet, email, or mobile application transmission is ever fully secure or error free. Email or other messages sent through the Service may not be secure. You should use caution whenever submitting information through the Service and take special care in deciding which information you provide us.

We cannot guarantee that transmissions of your personal information will be fully secure or that third parties will never be able to defeat our security measures. WE ASSUME NO LIABILITY FOR DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION DUE TO TRANSMISSION ERRORS, THIRD-PARTY ACCESS OR CAUSES BEYOND OUR CONTROL.

## VI. Links to Other Websites or Applications

This Privacy Policy applies only to the Service. The Service may contain links to other websites or apps or may forward users to other websites or apps that we may not own or operate. For example, the Online Store is owned and operated by a third party service provider. Your use of the Online Store is subject to the privacy policy provided on that website. The links from the Service do not imply that we endorse or have reviewed these websites or apps. The policies and procedures we describe here do not apply to these websites or apps. We neither can control nor are responsible for the privacy practices or content of these websites or apps. We suggest contacting these websites or app providers directly for information on their privacy policies. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our Service, and welcome any feedback about these linked websites and mobile applications.

## VII. Your Choices Regarding Your Information

We may periodically send you free newsletters, surveys, promotions, and other emails that directly promote the use of the Service. When you receive email communications from us, you may indicate a preference to stop receiving further communications from us and you will have the opportunity to "opt-out" by following the unsubscribe instructions provided in the email you receive or by contacting us.

## VIII. Do Not Track Policy

Your browser or device may offer you a "Do Not Track" option, which allows you to signal to operators of websites, web applications, mobile applications and services (including behavioral advertising services) that you do not wish such operators to track certain of your online activities over time and/or across different websites or applications. Our Service does not support Do Not Track requests at this time, which means that we or other third parties with which we are working will collect information about your online activity both during and after your use of the Service.

## IX. Children

We do not knowingly collect personal information from individuals under the age of 13. If you are under the age of 13, please do not submit any personal information through the Service. If you have reason to believe that we may have accidentally received personal information from an individual under age 13, please contact us immediately.

## X. Changes to Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to update or modify this Privacy Policy at any time and from time to time. Please review this Privacy Policy periodically, and especially before you provide any information. This Privacy Policy was made effective on the date indicated above. 

## XI. How to Contact Us

Please feel free to contact us if you have any questions about this Privacy Policy.

## XII. Your California Privacy Rights

Section 1798.83 of the California Civil Code permits California residents to request from a business, with whom the California resident has an established business relationship, certain information about the types of personal information the business has shared with third parties for those third parties’ direct marketing purposes and the names and addresses of the third parties with whom the business has shared such information during the immediately preceding calendar year. You may make one request each year by writing us at 1730 East Prospect RD, Fort Collins, CO 80553.
